REETIK PATEL

(479) 385-1212
reetikp@gmail.com
www.reetikpatel.me
www.linkedin.com/in/reetik

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a front-end engineer with a passion for creating intuitive, research backed user interfaces. The user always comes first! With over 7 years of building enterprise solutions, I emphasize maintainability and efficiency in my work. I'm able to pick up new processes and tools very quickly.

SKILLS ENGINEERING TOOLS

- Typescript/Javascript NextJS
- React
- Vue
- React Native
- Java
- Python

DESIGN TOOLS

- Sketch
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Zeplin

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

UNIVERSITY OF ARKANSAS

Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science Minor in Management

NN/G UX MASTER

Specialties in Interaction Design and UX Research

EXPERIENCE

XEROSEC LLC

Software Engineer | Jan 2024 - May 2024

- Designed, built, and released new frontend for a script sharing platform using NX monorepo and component library documented with Storybook
- Integrated authentication with Azure B2C
- Set up CI/CD pipelines with Github Actions to deploy to Azure

BILL.COM / DIVVY

Software Engineer | Oct 2022 - Dec 2023

- Built and released new budget management tools including policy management and import functionality for budget groups
- Greatly improved test coverage and code readability
- Worked on migrating existing Javascript monorepo to new federated Typescript repositories

WALMART GLOBAL TECH

Software Engineer | Nov 2016 - Sept 2022

- Created an admin UI to manage an internal notification platform integrated into associatefacing mobile applications
- Applied UX practices in documentation and example projects for React Native, Android, and iOS SDKs
- Maintained the Apple code signing process for all associate-facing iOS applications involving hundreds of certificates
- Applied CI/CD to streamline numerous support processes
- Worked with the AI/ML team on a mobile app to improve data entry for verifying stocked items